Aaron Yoshitake

linkedin.com/in/AaronHYoshi (970) 430-5606 AaronHYoshi@gmail.com

Full-stack product engineer with 9+ years of professional experience crafting rich Uls.

Perpetual learner who seeks out courses and passion projects, gains knowledge and skills, then leverages these to advance teams and companies.

Key Skills & Tools

Expert: JavaScript, React, Apollo Client, Redux, Node.js, Express, REST APIs, jQuery, HTML, Git Proficient: TypeScript, GraphQL, Apollo Server, React Native, React Native Web, MongoDB, CSS, Sketch, Figma Familiar: Webpack, SCSS, Testing Library, AWS, Angular, RxJS, Firebase, SQL, Python, Native iOS/Android

Professional Experience

Full-Stack Web & App Developer at Viasat, Inc.

January 2019 - October 2020

- Helped Viasat realize significant recurring savings on its customer service expenses by developing web and mobile apps that enable hundreds of thousands of residential internet subscribers to view status information and fix issues without calling Viasat's support line
- Built and updated these Web, iOS, and Android apps using React Native Web, sharing 80% of their code
- Took ownership of app auth and chat-explored needs by contacting stakeholders, proactively identified technical constraints, integrated with other teams' services, and reintegrated through multiple migrations
- Wrote end-to-end feature code: React containers and components; Apollo queries, links, and resolvers; and GraphQL and REST calls to external APIs—all completed, reviewed, and merged within 2-week sprints
- Refined designs per technical limitations and brand guidelines, working closely with designer teammates
- Investigated causes of application downtime detected while on-call, rolling back changes or pushing fixes
- Supported junior developers with technical and process issues; thoroughly tested and reviewed their code Frontend: React, React Native, React Native Web, Context API, Apollo Client, TypeScript, WebViews Backend: Node.js, GraphQL, Apollo Server, Express

Mobile App Developer at Viasat, Inc.

August 2017 - January 2019

- Constructed Viasat's first consumer-facing apps, used by hundreds of thousands of residential internet subscribers, saving Viasat enough on customer service to justify their development cost within months
- Wrote NativeScript Angular code and, later, React Native code to build these iOS and Android apps Frontend: NativeScript, Angular, NgRx, RxJS, React, React Native

Full-Stack Web Developer at Viasat, Inc.

June 2011 - August 2017

- Architected and built real-time network status and management UIs for smart grid cybersecurity systems; proposed and led the first use of Node.js, Express, and MongoDB within Viasat, to build its webserver
- Spearheaded development of Viasat's first React site, a prototype of later self-service apps and websites
- Authored user guides and design documentation, using Visio and Figma to illustrate system architecture, data flow between components, and interaction flow between screens

Frontends: React, Redux, jQuery, jQuery Desktop, Datatables, Bootstrap, Backbone.js, Socket.IO Backends: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, PHP, Python, Cornice, Pyramid, SQL

Side Projects

Founder and Principal Developer of Pick a Kit

June 2017 - Present

- Mine data about upcoming meal kits from 10 disparate data sources using a Node.js scraping library for HTML pages, isomorphic-fetch for REST APIs, and graphql-request for GraphQL endpoints
- Craft rich Uls that present this and other data, including a meal card carousel and pricing calculators
- Drive hundreds of new subscribers to affiliate services, earning thousands of dollars in commissions;
 donate over \$1000 to partner charity Weld Food Bank, including 100% of revenue for the year 2020
- Assign projects and training to junior devs, balancing their growth and timely completion of business goals
- Present prototypes and live website at UX Peer Review meetups; improve designs based on feedback

Frontend: React, Redux, Reselect, Bootstrap, React Helmet. Live at PickaKit.com

Backend: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, scrapelt, Tesseract

Co-founder and Principal Developer of Youtopia Project

June 2016 - Present

- Design, build, test, and update a custom Myers-Briggs personality assessment and test result pages for a personality magazine site with thousands of monthly active users
- Conducted stakeholder interviews with co-founders to identify shared and individual objectives; led debriefing session with all co-founders, facilitating discussion about key points and a redefined strategy
- Present prototypes and live pages at UX Peer Review meetups; improve designs based on feedback

Frontend: WordPress, jQuery. Live at YoutopiaProject.com

Backend: WordPress, PHP, MySQL

Sole Developer of many other web apps

December 2011 - September 2014

- Devised and developed several sites backed by Node.js 0.6.x, Express, and MongoDB, earning valuable early experience with the Node.js ecosystem that was critical to subsequent full-time projects at Viasat
- Designed and constructed a customizable, responsive productivity app based on my goal-tracking system
- Built the backend for a real-time Bitcoin poker site using Node.js, Express, Socket.IO, and Blockchain.info
- Presented prototypes and live websites at UX Peer Review meetups; improved designs based on feedback

Frontend: jQuery, AngularJS, Bootstrap. GitHub repo at github.com/airandfingers/rpwm-server

Backend: Node.js, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Blockchain.info, Socket.IO

Education

University of California, Berkeley

Bachelor's Degree, Computer Science. Coursework included Software Engineering, Algorithms, Security, Databases, Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, and Operating Systems

University of California San Diego Extension

Human-Computer Interaction coursework: Cognitive Consequences of Technology, Cognitive Ethnography, and Cognitive Design Studio

California State University Fullerton Extension

User Experience Design coursework: User-Centered Design for Web and Mobile Interfaces, Prototyping User-Centered Design Solutions, Concepts and Practices in Usability Testing